Second Dish
Episode 7
That dish has turmeric, pink peppercorns, cumin, coriander, and cloves.
（葉山(はやま)アキラ）
その皿　ターメリック
ピンクペッパー
クミン　コリアンダー
クローブ
右の皿　アムチュール
カルダモン
The right dish has amchoor, cardamom, dill, bay leaf, and savory.
ディル　ローリー　サボリ
The left dish has star anise, fennel, wild yams, and lemon balm.
左の皿はスターアニス
フェンネル
ワイルドヤム　レモンバーム
You're amazing, Hayama-kun!
（汐見潤(しおみじゅん)）さすが葉山君！
You identified all of them without being able to see or touch them!
視覚も触覚も封じた状態で
正解率100％！
Yeah, I'm perfectly ready.
ああ 完璧に仕上がってる
106... 107...
（黒木場(くろきば)リョウ）106…
107…
108... 109... 110...
108… 109… 110…
111...
111… 112…
112...
Looks like he's perfectly ready.
（薙切(なきり)アリス）
どうやら完璧に
仕上がっているようね
113...
（薙切(なきり)アリス）
どうやら完璧に
仕上がっているようね
（黒木場）113… 114…
114...
But...
（黒木場）113… 114…
（アリス）でも…
Air Freshener
Ugh!
もう！　汗まみれじゃない！
リョウ君 ばっちい！
Air Freshener
You're covered in sweat!
Ryou-kun, you're nasty!
Air Freshener
（黒木場）なっ…
I wanted to ask you to clean my room.
（アリス）
部屋の片づけを
お願いしたかったのに
Go take a shower, already!
さっさとシャワー
浴びてきなさい！
Miss!
（黒木場）お嬢
（アリス）ん？
Hm?
You're in a good mood,
despite losing to Yukihira Souma.
幸平創真に負けたってのに
ご機嫌っすね
（アリス）うっ…
That's why you lost, probably.
（黒木場）
そんなんだから負けちゃうんすよ
たぶん
フン　チープな挑発だこと
Hah, that's a poor attempt at provoking me,
but sure, I'll take it.
受けるけどね
Don't cry, even if you lose.
負けても泣かないでくださいよ
（観客の歓声）
I'll crush him!
ぶっつぶしてやる！
フン
誰かの付き人なんて肩書きの奴に
負ける気はしないな
I don't intend to lose
to somebody else's assistant.
Hm, so those two are next.
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）
ああ…　次はあの２人かぁ
どんな品になっかなぁ
I wonder how the match will go.
Why are you here acting like you belong?!
（薙切(なきり)えりな）
なぜ当然のように
ここにいるの？
VIP ROOM
Well, I was running late,
and the match was about to start.
（創真）
いやあ
もたもたしてたら―
もう試合
始まりそうだったし
Since I'll be facing whoever wins this round,
この２人の
どっちかと―
Out! Get out! Go away!
この２人の
どっちかと―
（えりな）
どいてよ どきなさいよ
あっち行って！
（えりな）
どいてよ どきなさいよ
あっち行って！
（えりな）
どいてよ どきなさいよ
あっち行って！
決勝で
当たるわけだからなぁ
Who do you think you are?!
（えりな）
この私を誰だと思ってるの？
君程度の料理人がぁ！
I need to get a good look.
（えりな）
この私を誰だと思ってるの？
君程度の料理人がぁ！
（創真）
しっかりと
観戦しとかないと
You're just a two-bit chef.
（えりな）
この私を誰だと思ってるの？
君程度の料理人がぁ！
Huh?
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）
あれ？　薙切さんと
一緒にいるの…
Look who's with Nakiri-san.
（水戸(みと)郁魅(いくみ)）ああ？
Souma-kun?
（恵）創真君？
（郁魅）ええっ？
What?
んんっ…
We'll now have the second match
of the semi-finals!
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）準決勝 第二試合
The theme is the same
as in the first match:
テーマは第一試合と同様
洋食のメイン 一品だ
a Western-style main dish.
Very well.
それでは―
Let the cooking...
調理ぃ 開始ぃ！
commence!
（観客の歓声）
♪～
omoiegaiteru imeeji yori haruka mukou gawa e
Far beyond the image I have in my mind
tsukuriagete yuku shinjitsu wa mada tooku
The reality I'm building up is still far away
hatenai tabiji
An endless journey
otagai no puraido wo togisumaseyou ze
Let's hone each other's pride
kotoba nante kazari wa hadakesaserya ii
Make people see that words are cheap and unimportant
butsukariai migakarete iku
We fight each other and hone our skills
Rolling stone
deai wa shockwave shockwave
Our encounters cause shockwaves
mada shiranai sekai e
We're reckless challengers
arukihajimeta mubou na chousensha sa
Heading toward a world as yet unexplored
te ni shita yaiba de ashita wo
With the blade in your hand
kirihirakeba iin darou
Open the way to the future
dareka no mon ja nai jibun dake no story
This is my story and no one else's
Cause we're still rough diamonds on the road
～♪
BEASTS DEVOURING EACH OTHER
（観客のざわめき）
Oh, Hayama's bringing out his ingredients.
（青木大吾(あおきだいご)）
おっ！
葉山が食材を出したぞ
Is that chicken?
（佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)）鶏肉か？
（郁魅）違う　あれは…
No.
That's...
Duck!
（吉野悠姫(よしのゆうき)）カモ！
His dish will depend on how well he takes advantage of duck's unique flavor profile.
（木久知(きくち)園果(そのか)）
カモ肉が持つ独特な風味
それをどう生かすかが
決め手になります
So he's Hayama Akira, the master of spices.
（角崎(つのざき)タキ）
香りの名手 葉山アキラか
He knows exactly what he's good at.
自分の長所を
理解しきってやがるな
A chef's sense of taste
（乾日向子(いぬいひなこ)）
料理人の味覚とは―
is a compendium of all the flavors they've experienced in the past.
過去 経験してきた様々な味の
引き出し
It's cumulative.
その累積によって作られる
（水原冬美(みずはらふゆみ)）
ああ　味覚に加え―
Yeah.
If you can add a sense of smell that's keen enough to tell apart individual ingredients of various spice mixtures,
スパイスミックスを
個別に嗅(か)ぎ分けられるほどの―
嗅覚(きゅうかく)が備われば―
you've basically gained
twice the momentum as a chef.
料理人は 倍の推進力を
手に入れたに等しい
In addition to having a
genius sense of smell,
（堂島）天性の嗅覚に加え―
he has been receiving the Tohtsuki education
from his first year in junior high.
中等部１年から遠月(とおつき) 正規の教育を
受けてきた―
Hayama Akira is one of the super elite.
スーパーエリート 葉山アキラ
After Nakiri Alice, he's a top candidate to become a member of the Elite Ten.
薙切アリスに次ぐ
十傑(じゅっけつ)入り有力候補の１人だ
Hey, about this match.
（男子生徒Ａ）まあ この試合…
Yeah, the odds are 8 or 9 to 10
that Hayama Akira will win.
（男子生徒Ｂ）
ああ　十中八九 葉山だろうな
Come to think of it,
（創真）
そういやあ 下馬評じゃ
葉山が圧倒的有利って―
according to Mitsuru, rumor has it that the students all favor Hayama to win.
みつるが言ってたな
What do you think, Nakiri?
薙切は どう思うよ？
Well, I was once in the same
class as Kurokiba-kun.
そうね
以前 黒木場君と同じクラスに
なったことがあるわ
The dishes he cooked up
in that class were far from good.
授業で彼が出した料理は―
お世辞にも
よい品とは言えなかったわね
It wasn't enough to fail the class,
不合格になるような
水準ではないけれど―
but the dishes lacked spirit,
どこか気の抜けた皿
as though they were made just well enough to pass the class.
ただ授業をこなすためだけの
料理という感じで―
All the more reason that I was so surprised by his original creation in the preliminaries.
それだけに 予選で見た
彼のオリジナル料理には驚かされた
Oh, that's why you're hopeless, Erina!
もう　だから
えりなはダメなのよ
（えりな）あっ…
（アリス）
ンッフ　ごめんあそばせ
Excuse me!
（えりな）んんんっ…
Ryou-kun's true talent cannot
be measured by logic alone.
リョウ君の実力は
論理だけでは測れないのよ
（観客のどよめき）
Eel?!
（男子生徒Ｃ）ウナギだとぉ？
マジか　魚介が得意ってのは
聞いてたけど―
Seriously?
I'd heard seafood was his specialty,
but this is unexpected.
意外なとこ 突いてきたなぁ
Will he broil it Japanese-style?
かば焼き… なわけねえか
お題は洋食だし
Nah, the topic is Western cuisine.
French and other foreign cuisines
include dishes that use eel.
フランス料理を始め 諸外国でも
ウナギを使ったレシピは存在するわ
日本料理だけの素材ではないの
It's not an ingredient limited
to Japanese cuisine.
Eel.
（えりな）ウナギ…
ひょっとして彼の狙いは…
Could he be trying to make...
Hey, about what you said earlier,
なあ さっきの話だけど
どういう意味だ？
what did you mean?
That logic isn't enough
to measure his abilities.
論理だけじゃ測れないって
ンフッ
I didn't think that you'd talk about
mind over matter, Alice.
アリスが精神論を語るなんて…
You're all about creating dishes
using science and logic, aren't you?
あなた 科学とロジックで
料理を作り上げるのが信条でしょ
This has nothing to do with "mind over matter."
これは精神論でも
何でもないのよ
It's just a fact that Ryou-kun's dishes are infused with something that goes beyond mere logic.
現実として
リョウ君の料理の味には―
論理を超えたものが
宿っている
（黒木場）勝たなきゃ
I have to win.
If I don't win,
勝たなければ
俺には どこにも居る所がない
I have nowhere I can call home!
If I don't win here,
今ここで勝たなきゃ―
I'll die!
死ぬ！
You see, Ryou-kun survived
（アリス）リョウ君はね―
in a kitchen straight out of hell.
地獄のような調理場で
生き抜いてきたの
He only had his skills to rely on
in a horrible environment.
劣悪な環境の中
頼れるのは自分の腕だけ
In order to live, Ryou-kun gained
an absolute focus on taste,
生活するために
リョウ君が獲得したのは―
絶対的な味への集中力
and a fierce combativeness
that smolders within him!
身を焦がすほどに
自分を燃やす闘争心
Ryou-kun and I have competed in cooking matches almost every day,
私とリョウ君は ほとんど毎日
料理勝負をしてきたけど―
and he's never slacked off in any of them.
１日たりとも
リョウ君が手を抜いた日はないわ
Whenever he's in a match,
ひと度 勝負となれば
本気で噛(か)み殺しにかかってくる
he's absolutely determined
to shred you into pieces.
If there is something I, myself,
lack in a match, that would be...
勝負において 私に足りないものが
あるとすれば それは…
あ…
Nope, never mind.
（アリス）
ううん 何でもないの
If there is something I lack,
（アリス）
足りないものがあるとすれば
それは―
it's a fierce obsession to win,
an obsession as hot as molten lava!
勝負に対する
溶岩のような執着心
If there's anyone here who has that in spades,
it's Ryou-kun. I'm sure of it.
今 この会場にいる
料理人の中で―
最も それを強く備えているのは
リョウ君
断言できるわ
An eel knife! It's a special knife for filleting eel.
ウナギを開くことに特化した
ウナギ包丁
So he's well-versed in Japanese
culinary techniques, as well.
日本料理の技術にも
精通してるのか
This face-off is reminiscent of a match between a
Stellar's sea eagle that has always flown high above,
（堂島）この対決カードを
例えるならば―
常に高みを飛び続けてきた
オオワシと―
and a vicious tiger who seeks to drag
its prey down to the ground with its jaws!
全てに噛みつき
地に ねじ伏せる猛虎
（虎の鳴き声）
（オオワシの鳴き声）
I don't sense any heat from you
about our battle. I don't like that.
（黒木場）気に食わねえな
勝負に対する温度がねえ
（葉山）んっ…
This is war!
ここは戦場だ！
勝ち残る覚悟のない奴は失せろ！
Get out if you're not gunning to win.
You're right.
そうだな
I may not be as focused on winning as you.
勝とう勝とうって意識は
お前よりは希薄かもしれないなぁ
But the reason for that is simple.
理由は簡単
With my sense of smell,
この鼻があれば
お前に負けるほうが難しい
it's hard to imagine how
I could lose against you.
What did you say?!
何だと！
Now...
さあ―
sound the ultimate melody of fragrance.
最上の香りを奏でろ！
うおおおお！
The fragrance of spices and
the duck are intertwined!
カモ肉とスパイスが
絡み合って…
It's unbelievable!
（青木･佐藤）たまんね～！
（においを嗅ぐ音）
使ってるスパイスは
コリアンダーとフェンネル
He's using coriander, fennel, oregano, and...
オレガノ　えっと あとは…
んんっ…
うわああ！
複雑すぎて分かんないよぉ！
I can't tell! It's too complex!
ふおおお～
How can you create such a wonderful aroma?
どうやったら こんな見事な香りを
作り出せるんでしょう
It's spicy, yet mellow.
スパイシーなのに まろやか
ほのかに甘いのに香ばしい
Faintly sweet, yet fragrant.
You can practically feel the presence of royalty.
（大泉柿之進(おおいずみかきのしん)）
もはや王者の風格すら
感じさせるわい
今彼は この空間の
支配者となっている
In this moment, he dominates this space.
ん？　何だ あいつ
さっきまでの勢いは どうした？
What's with him?
Where did all his energy go?
Was he discouraged by the
applause for his opponent?
相手への歓声で
萎縮してしまったんでしょうか
He doesn't even hear the audience.
歓声なんて聞こえてないわ
今 リョウ君の感覚器官は
素材の焼き色―
Right now, Ryou-kun's only sensing
the degree of browning of the eel,
the sizzling sound and smell of fat,
油のはじける音と匂い
ウナギの重さ―
and the weight of the eel.
He's focused only on what's
happening in the pan.
フライパンの中の情報しか
拾っていない
Kick all my senses into full throttle.
（黒木場）
全神経をフルスロットル
火入れの最高の瞬間を逃さねえ
Don't miss the exact moment when the eel's
reached cooked perfection!
Come!
来い　来い　来い！
Now!
ここだ！　焼きやがれ！
It's done!
やっぱり黒木場君は
マトロートで来たわね
Like I thought, Kurokiba-kun's
going for matelote.
マトロート？
Matelote?
It's a cooking method where fish
is braised with wine.
魚をワインで煮る調理法のことよ
Huh.
へえ～
Oh?
あれ？　つーか さっきウナギを
開いてたのに 元に戻したんだな
Wait, though he split the eel open,
he put it back together.
He wrapped the eel in caul fat to restore its original shape before cooking it.
クレピーヌで包んで―
ウナギ本来の形に巻き直してから
焼いていたの
Caul fat's the mesh-like thing that
covers beef and pork organs, right?
クレピーヌって 牛や豚の内臓を
覆ってる網みたいなやつだよな
That's right.
（アリス）
そう 脂によってコクが付加され
インパクトが高まる
The fat adds richness of flavor,
increasing the dish's impact.
It's a very Ryou-kun thing to do.
リョウ君らしい料理だわ
Fluffy mashed potatoes
and home-made brioche.
（えりな）
ほくほくのマッシュポテト
加えて自家製のブリオッシュ
So he deals out the many cards at his disposal to overwhelm his opponents.
豊富な持ち札を存分に注ぎ込んで
相手を圧倒する
That's how he's been constructing the destructive power of his dishes.
彼の料理の破壊力は
こうして構築されていたのね
You can try to win over the audience with your aroma theatrics as much as you want,
（黒木場）お前が いくら
香りのパフォーマンスで―
場の空気を作ろうと
俺には関係ねえ
but I don't give a shit.
I'll just tear right through it!
食い破るだけだ！
はっ！
I have my own cards too.
（葉山）
持ち札なら こっちにもある
Besides, what's the point
of having a lot of cards
それに どれだけカードが
あろうと―
if you can't master them?
それを使いこなせなきゃ
意味がない！
Hayama's always been calm before.
いつも冷静な葉山が…
Now he's like a totally different person!
まるで別人みたい
He's never had to show his claws before,
これまで
さらす必要のなかった爪を―
今ようやく さらけ出した
but now he finally has.
That's what his laugh seems to say.
（堂島）そんな笑い方だ
（葉山）ハッ
It's done.
完成だ
Candidate Hayama is first to serve his dish!
（川島麗(かわしまうらら)）
先に披露するのは葉山選手
Its rich aroma has already enveloped the arena!
芳醇(ほうじゅん)な香りが―
既に会場を包み込んでいます
Here is my dish, Canard Apicius.
（葉山）
カモのアピシウス風でございます
（角崎･木久知）ああ…
It's the dish said to have been beloved by Apicius,
a gourmand in Roman times.
ローマの美食家 アピシウス氏が
愛したと言われる品
It glistens from the caramelized honey.
（乾）
カラメル化した蜂蜜が
つやつやと…
The spices sprinkled across
the duck meat are very fragrant.
カモ肉一面に まぶしたスパイスが
匂い立つ
The aroma's enough to make you melt.
香りだけでも
とろけそうなのに―
What will happen once you take an actual bite?!
こんなの口に入れたら
どうなってしまうの？
Let's have a taste.
それでは実食だ
（５人）あむっ…
（５人）んんっ！
（乾）うわあ～！
（水原）わああ～！
What a gorgeous and spicy aroma piercing through my body!
全身を突き抜けるゴージャスで
スパイシーな芳香！
Even after you've chewed
and swallowed the bite,
咀嚼(そしゃく)して飲み込んでも 香りが
ずっと鼻と口に広がり続けて…
the fragrance continues to spread throughout your nose and mouth!
ああ～ 幸せ～！
I'm so happy!
What an unbelievable
combination of fragrances!
とんでもない香りのコンボ！
I've been seized by
（角崎）香りの魔力に…
the talons of aroma magic!
（２人）わしづかみぃ！
Though we lump them together as spices,
each has unique characteristics that are limitless.
（堂島）
一口にスパイスと言えども
その特性は数限りない
ピリリと からいものや
ほのかに甘いもの
Some are quite hot,
others faintly sweet.
Some are refreshing and astringent,
爽やかな清涼感があるものに
渋味の強いもの
while others are bitter.
This dish demonstrates full command of their delicate power balance.
そのパワーバランスを
自在に操った この料理は―
It would not be possible without his sense of smell!
彼の嗅覚なしには成立しない！
Full frontal assault!
総攻撃だ！
Fragrance is what will rule the culinary world.
香りこそが
これからの料理を支配する
No matter how many cards
you may add to your deck,
どれだけ手札をそろえようと
お前のカードじゃ俺には届かねえよ
your cards would never be my equal.
（創真）黒木場の目…
（えりな）えっ？
Kurokiba's eyes...
What?
They haven't lost all hope.
（創真）まだ死んでない
Hayama Akira.
葉山アキラ　お前から
ようやく勝負の温度を感じたぜ
I finally sense the heat of battle within you.
Cooking
Battle Card
It wouldn't be worth fighting back otherwise!
Cooking
Battle Card
そうでなきゃ食い応えがねえ！
Cooking
Battle Card
The challenger is Candidate Kurokiba!
（麗）
さあ 挑むは黒木場選手！
What ace does he have up his sleeve as a specialist in seafood cuisine?
得意とする魚介料理で
どんな切り札を見せるのか？
Have a taste!
味わいやがれ！
My dish is Eel Matelote!
ウナギのマトロート！
Oh, my!
まあ！　なんて力強い
ボリューム感なんでしょう
What a massive portion size!
The use of caul fat during the cooking process has heightened the eel's juiciness!
クレピーヌの効果もあって―
ウナギのジューシーさが
より際立っています
Hmph.
（角崎）
フン　香りの豊かさは
余裕で負けてる
In terms of the aroma, he falls far short.
威勢だけいい奴に
どうせ ろくな品は…
No one who's all bark and no bite
can serve a decent dish—
（黒木場）
ウダウダ言ってねえで早く食え
冷める
Quit yappin' and eat before it gets cold.
Oh?
ああ？
What the hell?! Want me
to teach you some manners?!
んだ てめえ！　礼儀から
たたき込んでやろうか マジ！
If you think you can act up
just because you're a student,
学生だから粗相が許されると
思ってんだったら―
I can teach you different right here, right now!
今すぐ体に たたき込んでやる！
ウガウガウガ…
（木久知）
タキ先輩 抑えて
抑えて
Stay calm, Taki-senpai!
Stay calm!
Now, let's have a taste.
さあ 実食だ
Oh, my! The eel has been simmered
through. It's so tender.
わあ！　じっくり煮込まれて
ほっくほく
The eel was marinated in red wine with cinnamon before it was cooked,
焼く前に シナモンや赤ワインで
マリネして―
which imparts a fresh flavor.
爽やかな風味をつけている
I've rigged the eel with explosives.
（黒木場）
あのウナギには火薬を仕込んだ
It's got a detonation device designed to blow you out of the running!
お前を飛ばすための
とっておきの発火装置だ
はふっ… ん…
（木久地）ううーっ！
What is it?
何？
（角崎）口の中に走る鮮烈な刺激
What's this electrifying jolt in my mouth?!
In the eel, Kurokiba hid...
ウナギの中に
黒木場が仕込んでいたのは…
a surprise! Plums!
不意打ち　プラムだ！
Cooking
Battle Card
Plum
Plums?
プラムって すもも？
Japanese plums?!
He paired plums with eel?!
ウナギに すももだってえ？
The slick eel fat has been infused
with the plums' fruity acidity,
（木久地）たぷたぷと
潤沢なウナギの脂に―
プラムのフルーティーな酸味が
じゅわっと広がって―
脳天に来る おいしさ！
creating a taste sensation
that goes right to your brain!
ああ… しびれちゃった…
I'm numb.
The eel was stuffed with reconstituted dried plums,
水で戻したプラムを
ウナギに巻き込み―
then wrapped with caul fat.
クレピーヌで包んだ
So that's what you meant.
さっき言ったのは
こういうことか
It's an explosion of acidity from the plums.
プラムによる
酸味の爆発ってわけかよ
Shut up and watch.
黙って見てろ
Next!
次だ　つけ合わせのブリオッシュと
マッシュポテト　そいつらに―
Take the brioche and mashed potatoes
and dip them into the sauce that's full of umami from the simmered eel.
ウナギを煮詰め うま味を
凝縮させた そのソースを絡めろ
Make sure to add some of the eel flesh, and shove the whole package into your mouth!
ウナギの身も一緒くたにして
全部まとめて頬張るんだ
Keep on eating, with no shame,
（黒木場）
さあ はしたなく食いつけよ
until you can't stand up anymore.
足腰立たなくなるまでなぁ
Damn!
（角崎）
くそぉ！　これは遠月学園の
美食の祭典だぞ
This is a festival of gourmet food
at Tohtsuki Academy!
He should try to be more civil!
少しは つつましくしろってんだ
But!
けど…
（つばを飲む音）
This is where things will really explode!
火薬が本当に炸裂(さくれつ)するのは―
ここだぁ！
（乾）うん うん…
（水原）んっ んっ…
The mashed potatoes' entangling texture...
（乾）マッシュポテトの
絡むような食感と…
The fluffy brioche...
（水原）ほわほわのブリオッシュ
The eel's sweet fat and the plums' acidity...
（木久地）
そしてウナギの あま～い脂と
プラムの酸味が暴れ回る
They're all rioting in my mouth!
All the flavors are melding
into one harmonious whole!
（４人）
全ての味が混然一体に！
This is different from Hayama Akira's bewitching flavors
that threaten to take you to nirvana.
（堂島）
葉山アキラの人を昇天させるような
幻惑の味とは違う
This is an explosive burst
meant to pierce any defense!
一点突破の爆発
獲物を残らず
地に屈服させる うまさ！
Flavors so delicious that they subdue all prey!
Shit. I can't resist!
（角崎）
チクショウ　あらがえない…
こいつの前では
私は なり下がる
I am a lesser being before him.
I have become the prey!
捕食される側に！
I bet you thought you had won.
（黒木場）
勝ったつもりでいたんだろ
（葉山）んっ…
（黒木場）捕まえたぞ
Caught you!
うっ…
This concludes the evaluation!
（麗）
これにて審査は終了！
判定に入ります
Time for the final assessment.
Judges, please cast your vote for the
candidate who served the better dish!
より美味であったほうに投票を！
（観客のざわめき）
The vote's finally starting.
いよいよ決まるぞ
But...
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）でも…
The judges are paralyzed.
審査員が固まってるぅ～
Until now, all the matches have
been decided right away.
今までの試合は即決だったのに
百戦錬磨の卒業生たちが
決めあぐねてるのか？
Our alums are having trouble deciding, despite all the experience they have?
（黒木場）くっうううう…
（乾）うっ…
I've decided!
決めました
私は葉山君だと思います！
I believe my vote is for Hayama-kun!
くうっ
I vote for Hayama Akira, as well.
私も 葉山アキラに１票
（男子生徒Ｄ）２票 入ったぜ
He's got two votes.
So Hayama's the stronger candidate.
（男子生徒Ｅ）葉山が強いか
（男子生徒Ｆ）決まりかな？
Maybe it's decided, then.
（丸井善二(まるいぜんじ)）やっぱり葉山か？
So it's Hayama, after all.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）
確かに見事な皿だったからな
His dish was impressive.
I believe my vote is for Kurokiba Ryou.
俺は… 黒木場リョウだと思う
But why?
どうしてですか？
His dish's rich flavors leveraged
the seafood's potential.
魚介を生かした濃厚な おいしさ
I saw sophistication in that
masculine, destructive flavor!
俺は あの雄々しい破壊力の中に
確かな品位を見た！
I judge his dish to be worthy of
acknowledgment in the Autumn Selection.
選抜で評価されるに値する一皿だと
判断する
も～う！
Which one should it be?
（角崎）どっちだ　どっちにする？
Both expressed their individuality in their dish.
双方とも自分らしい個性は
しっかりと皿に表現していた
But the one whose dish had the greater impact was...
その上で 料理で
より強い印象を与えたのは…
ぬあああ！　クソがぁ！
Shit!
私も 黒木場リョウ！
I also vote for Kurokiba Ryou!
（観客のどよめき）
（黒木場）へっ
This is unbelievable.
すっごいことになったよ
It's a split vote.
完全に意見が割れたわ
This is almost like a Cooking Battle!
こうなると
ほとんど食戟(しょくげき)じゃねえか
（伊武崎）ああ
（丸井）木久知園果シェフが―
Yeah.
It all hangs on Chef Kikuchi Sonoka's vote.
誰を支持するかで決まる
（木久知）決められない…
I can't decide.
（観客のざわめき）
Each dish was superb.
どちらの品も見事でした
I can't rank one over the other.
私には優劣をつけられない
Cut the bullshit!
ふざけてんじゃねえ！
（木久知）ひいぃぃぃ！
（黒木場）これは勝負だぞ！
This is a match!
It's not over until one of us falls!
どっちかが倒れるまで
終われるか！
Get your act together and decide!
結論出しやがれ コラァ！
ひいいいやああ…
What's the meaning of this, judge?
（来賓Ａ）
どういうつもりだ 審査員！
Make up your mind!
（来賓Ｂ）はっきりしたまえ！
Are you mocking a serious competition?!
真剣勝負をコケにするのか？
（木久知）あ…
（堂島）彼女の意見も―
I can understand where she's coming from.
分からないではない
The two are so equally matched.
それほどに両者の力は拮抗(きっこう)している
運営委員の諸君
Organizers, a word.
What is it, Chef Doujima?
（一色慧(いっしきさとし)）
何でしょうか 堂島シェフ
Huh?
あれ？　いつの間に？
When'd they leave?
食戟のルールであれば
どうしても決着がつかない場合―
If this were a Cooking Battle,
and a final decision could not be reached,
勝負預かりとして
後日 再試合を行うことになる
there would be a rematch at a later date to determine the final outcome,
そうだな？
am I right?
That's correct.
そのとおりです
But this is the Autumn Selection.
しかし これは秋の選抜
ご来賓の方々も―
Our honored guests and the judges all have very busy schedules.
そして もちろん審査員の皆さんも
大変ご多忙でいらっしゃる
Pragmatically speaking, it would be impossible to schedule a rematch, unfortunately.
再試合の日時を確保することは
現実的に不可能です　残念ながら
Given that, I have a suggestion.
そこで提案だ
のっぴきならない この状況を
打破する手段が１つだけあるぞ
There is one way to resolve this dilemma.
ああっ…
２人とも上げてしまえばいい
Let both of them proceed.
秋の選抜 史上初
三つ巴(どもえ)の決勝戦を提案する！
I propose that there be a three-way final round
for the very first time in the Autumn Selections!
（観客のどよめき）
What?!
A three-way?!
（女子生徒Ａ）三つ巴？
But there is no precedent!
（えりな）
しかし 過去に一度も
前例がありません
The judges cannot simply decide to—
審査員の一存で
決められることでは…
That's an interesting proposal!
審査員の一存で
決められることでは…
（薙切仙左衛門(なきりせんざえもん)）
その提案 面白い！
（えりな）あ…
（薙切仙左衛門(なきりせんざえもん)）
その提案 面白い！
（えりな）ああ…
I will approve it with my authority as the director of this academy!
のもうではないか
学園総帥(そうすい)の権限で
黒木場リョウ
葉山アキラの試合は引き分け
Kurokiba Ryou and Hayama Akira's match is determined to be a draw!
Both will proceed to the final round!
両者 勝ち上がり
決勝は―
幸平創真を加えた３名で
戦うものとする！
Yukihira Souma will join
the two of them in the final match!
（観客の歓声）
（伊武崎･丸井）あ ああ…
Candidate Kurokiba, congratulations for proceeding to the final round.
（佐々木由愛(ささきゆあ)）
黒木場選手…
決勝進出おめでとうございます
あの… ぜひ意気込みを…
Um, any thoughts on moving forward?
何が“おめでとう”だ
コラァ！
Congratulations, my ass!
俺は認めてねえんだよ！
I haven't accepted this result!
（由愛）
うわああああ！
ああ～！
They only delayed the outcome, you little shits!
（由愛）
うわああああ！
ああ～！
（黒木場）
決着を先延ばしにしやがって
クソがあああああ！
（黒木場）
決着を先延ばしにしやがって
クソがあああああ！
（黒木場）
決着を先延ばしにしやがって
クソがあああああ！
（笛の音）
（黒木場）
決着を先延ばしにしやがって
クソがあああああ！
（黒木場）
決着を先延ばしにしやがって
クソがあああああ！
（アリス）
リョウ君 ハウス
ハウスよ！
Ryou-kun! Heel! Heel!
Well, let's see.
ええ そうですね
黒木場選手に並ばれてしまったのは
悔しいですが―
I regret that Candidate Kurokiba
and I fought to a draw,
しっかり切り替えて
次の試合に備えたいと思います
but I'd like to switch gears and
prepare for my next match.
（早津田(そうつだ)みつる）幸平先輩！
Yukihira-senpai!
Senpai, please tell us your thoughts moving forward to the final match too.
先輩も決勝への意気込みを
お願いします！
えっ　俺もか？
Huh? I have to say something?
ああ… 何だかむずがゆいな
This is kind of awkward.
ええと 予選では
あの２人と同じＡブロックで―
Uh... Well, in the prelims, I was in the same group as those two.
葉山に１点差
Hayama beat me by one point,
and Kurokiba scored the same as me.
黒木場にも
並ばれちゃったんだよなぁ
I've wanted to defeat both of them fair and square before moving on up,
上に行く前に―
２人とも ちゃんと
負かしときたかったんで―
so I feel lucky to have this chance.
そのチャンスをもらえて
お得って感じっすわ
（黒木場）何っ！
（葉山）んっ…
（麗）
以上を持ちまして
準決勝は終了となります
We now conclude the semi-finals.
（照明の消える音）
続きまして 運営委員会から
決勝の対決テーマを発表します
Next, the organizers will announce
the theme for the finals!
続きまして 運営委員会から
決勝の対決テーマを発表します
Oh?
おお～
決勝は毎年 秋の旬の食材が
テーマになるんす
Every year, the finals have a seasonal ingredient as their theme.
It's considered only appropriate as a choice to conclude the Autumn Selection.
それこそ秋の選抜を締めくくるのに
ふさわしいってわけです
（一色）はっ！
The topic is Pacific saury.
テーマはサンマです
（観客の歓声）
In olden times,
（一色）
古くは 民衆だけが口にする―
it was considered lowbrow fish,
eaten only by the common masses.
いわゆる下魚(げざかな)と
見なされていましたが―
近年では
高級店でも取り扱われ―
But in recent years, it has been served in high-end restaurants
諸外国のレストランでも
登場するようになりました
and made appearances in restaurants overseas.
そんなサンマを使った一品
それが決勝のお題となります
A dish using this fish will be
the theme of the final round.
葉山アキラ　黒木場リョウ
幸平創真
Hayama Akira.
Kurokiba Ryou.
Yukihira Souma.
I feel fate's strange hand at work because
these three are advancing to the final round.
くしくも この３人が
勝ち残ったことに―
不思議な縁を感じます
なぜならサンマは
極めて香り高く―
For Pacific saury is an extremely fragrant fish,
a highly valued seafood ingredient,
重宝される魚介であり―
and a fish with deep ties
to the common people's table!
大衆にも関わり深い
It is therefore an ingredient that allows each of you to capitalize on your own strengths!
三者三様に 自分の強みを
生かせる食材というわけです
The finals will be held in ten days.
その決戦は10日後
最高の戦いをお約束します！
I trust that it will be the ultimate battle!
♪～
seki wo kitta nodo kara te ga deru hodo
An intensely burning desire burst forth
hoshiku nattan da boku ja nai betsu no dareka
But not from me, from someone else
yume to kibou hoka ni nani ga iru to
Where's the me who believed that
omoeta koro no boku wa ima izuko e?
All one needs is to have hopes and dreams
nagai mono ni makarete ushinatta michishirube
Wrapped around something long, my compass was lost
sei to shi no hazama ni wa sunoo duroppu ga sakimidareru
On the border of life and death, snow drops bloom
nanika no machigai de kudakechitte shimatta nara
If by some mistake they get smashed
semete boku no nukegara ni hanataba wo soete
At least put flowers on the empty husk
konna mon ka na konna mon deshou
Is that the way things are? Yes, it is
akirame da to omowaretatte kamawanai kedo
You can call it resignation if you want
boku rashiku nai boku rashiku nai
But that's not me, that's not me
dare ni mo datte tsukureru mon ni kachi wa nai
There's no value in something just anyone could make
～♪
Hayama-kun!
（汐見）葉山君！
葉山く～ん！　決勝だあああ！
The finals!
I know. Calm down, Jun.
分かったから騒ぐなよ 潤
C'mon, how can you stay so calm?
もう！　どうしてそんな
冷静でいられるの？
I'm so happy for you!
先生は… 先生はうれしいよ！
Sorry, let me go blow my nose!
ごめん
ちょっと鼻かんでくるね～！
Yeah, Hayama.
（創真）そうだよ 葉山
You should stop trying to put up a calm front and let yourself be frustrated.
冷静なふりなんかで取り繕わねえで
悔しがればいいのに
There's nothing to be frustrated about.
悔しがる理由がないな
Oh?
何？
My plans to advance to the finals and then win the Autumn Selection are still on schedule.
決勝へ進む　優勝を勝ち取る
予定は滞りなく進んでるさ
（黒木場）ハッ！
（葉山）ん？
Even though our match was a draw,
（黒木場）
勝負に引き分けたってのに
まだ格上気取りかよ スパイス野郎
you're still putting on airs, spice bastard?
You're only good at using spices.
You're a one-trick pony.
スパイスしか能がない
ワンパターンの料理人
I see right through all your cards now.
もうてめえの手の内は見えたんだ
次で仕留める
I'll get you next time.
幸平 お前もだ
You too, Yukihira.
What are you doing?
何してるの　帰るわよ
Let's go home.
Oh...
は～…
Excuse us.
ごめんあそばせ
（黒木場）じゃ お疲れ～
Later. Good work.
Don't deflate without warning like that.
（葉山）急に力抜くんじゃねえよ…
I can't keep up with all the mood swings.
（創真）
テンションの差に
ついていけね～
Later, Yukihira.
（葉山）
じゃあな 幸平
今のうちにヘラヘラ笑ってろよ
Enjoy grinning while you still can.
Miss, can you fight me in a cooking match as soon as we get back?
お嬢 帰ったらすぐ
料理勝負してもらっていいすか？
（アリス）ん？
こんな不完全燃焼のままじゃ
決勝の日まで眠れやしない
I don't think I'll be able to sleep until the final round, because there's no closure.
（葉山）
ハッ スパイスしか能がない… か
So I'm only good at using spices?
Today's semi-finals were amazing!
（女子生徒Ｂ）
今日の準決勝 すごかったわねえ
（女子生徒Ｃ）ひっ…
（女子生徒Ｂ･Ｄ）ああ？
（３人）あっ…
Fine, I'll show you, then.
（葉山）
いいぜ　だったら見せてやるよ
香りがいざなう本当の世界を
The true world where fragrance beckons.
The final round, huh.
（創真）
決勝か…　やっとここまで来たな
I finally got here.
No, this is just the beginning.
いや　まだまだ こっからだ
Let's go see how things look higher up!
眺めに行くか
もっと高い場所の景色！
DAYS LEFT UNTIL THE FINALS: 10
NEXT TIME
BATTLE OF SEASONALITY
Next time, "Battle of Seasonality."